<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Ignacio Pascale</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Ignacio Pascale</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/blogs/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Ignacio
 Learn about me Hi, my name is Ignacio Pascale. I was born in Buenos Aires, Argentina.
Buenos Aires City
 I always held strong family ties with my family. In 1910, my great-grand parents arrived in Argentina from the South of Italy, in persuit of a better life. Italian families can be quite particular: family is the most important value.
Ever since childhood, my parents have taught me the values of helping people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do Americans behave on Social Media?</title>
      <link>/blogs/social_american_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/social_american_society/</guid>
      <description>General Social Survey (GSS) How does the American Society relate to social media, technology and education?
The General Social Survey (GSS) gathers data on American society in order to monitor and explain trends in attitudes, behaviours, and attributes. Many trends have been tracked for decades, so one can see the evolution of attitudes, etc in American Society.
In this blog post, we analyze data from the 2016 GSS sample data, using it to estimate values of population parameters of interest about US adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many bikes will be hired on a regular day on Summer?</title>
      <link>/blogs/londonbikes_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/londonbikes_regression/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the following workshop I will analyse the data set londonBikes from the UK Government. I will try to build a model in which to quantify the relationship of hired bikes and some explanatory variables using regression analysis, and shortly after I will use that model to predict the number hirings for a regular day in London in Summer with more than 15 degrees Celcius.
The workflow will proceed as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How popular is Donald Trump?</title>
      <link>/blogs/trump_popular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/trump_popular/</guid>
      <description>Mr Donald Trump is undoubtely one of the most controversial persons in the world. Some people love him, others not so much. And there’s a lot going on about his approval index.
But how popular is, in reality, Mr. President?
fivethirtyeight.com has detailed data on all polls that track the president’s approval. You can find this information on the link.
In this blogpost, we will download the data set approval_pollist to analyse Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>